<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips on Coders Digest</title>
    <link>http://abhipandey.com/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips on Coders Digest</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://abhipandey.com/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding launcher shortcut in Fedora</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/adding-launcher-shortcut-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/adding-launcher-shortcut-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many apps do not come pre-built in rpm format for Fedora so you&amp;rsquo;d have to download the &lt;strong&gt;tar&lt;/strong&gt; file for it.&#xA;To run the app, you would have to go to the saved folder and then either double cilck or run the command through&#xA;command line. By default, that app won&amp;rsquo;t be accessible through the &lt;code&gt;Super&lt;/code&gt; key&amp;rsquo;s universal search or&#xA;as a regular application in *&lt;strong&gt;Show Applications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s a way around and it is an easy one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running invoke from other folders</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/running-invoke-from-other-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/running-invoke-from-other-folders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on big projects, sometimes, you have &lt;code&gt;invoke&lt;/code&gt; tasks lying around&#xA;in different places. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to merge them together&#xA;but rather help each other out as and when needed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such way for this would be to search for invoke tasks from other folders&#xA;and run them directly when they can be used.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had to go for this approach for a monolithic repo where multiple projects&#xA;were being built in mostly similar style with minor modifications.&#xA;All of them would have the same set of commands along with same style of running those commands.&#xA;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to set up the same &lt;code&gt;invoke&lt;/code&gt; task for all individual projects but rather&#xA;a common set of tasks that could be re-used by each one of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using TODO in Fedora</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/using-todo-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 21:17:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/using-todo-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started using Fedora for work and had to manage a lot of tasks on various projects.&#xA;The list was big enough and there&amp;rsquo;s no proper support for Evernote in linux, my trusty todo list manager&#xA;or ToDo list manager by AbstractSpoon. Decided to try post-it notes but my list was changing on an&#xA;ad-hoc basis. Finally came across an &lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/570/todotxt/&#34;&gt;extension Todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turned out this was just what I was looking for. I started putting all of my tasks in it, with proper categorization.&#xA;Behind the scenes it is an extremely simple app which has only two files, both saved in &lt;code&gt;~/.local/share/todo.txt/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up your VIM... Your style</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/setting-up-your-vim...-your-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 15:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/setting-up-your-vim...-your-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing code using VIM can be a bit overwhelming but it helps creating a few shortcuts there to make your life easier. Here I will discuss a few.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First of all, it is always a good idea to set up your tabs and spaces&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set up shortcuts for:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toggling of Auto-Indent&lt;/code&gt; while pasting source text; very useful in code (&lt;em&gt;F2&lt;/em&gt; in my provided script)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toggling of Auto-Scroll&lt;/code&gt; of Split windows (&lt;em&gt;F3&lt;/em&gt; in my provided script)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Macro for Folding functions&lt;/code&gt; within the source code (&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;@q&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in my provided script)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Smart case search&lt;/code&gt; - based on whether the input is in caps or not&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Toggling of Mouse Usage&lt;/code&gt; in VIM window - to allow quick selection of text (&lt;em&gt;F12&lt;/em&gt; in my provided script)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the provided script below to have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
