<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Coders Digest</title>
    <link>http://abhipandey.com/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Coders Digest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 07:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abhipandey.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambda Basics with Python using Github Webhooks or API Gateway</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/11/lambda-basics-with-python-using-github-webhooks-or-api-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/11/lambda-basics-with-python-using-github-webhooks-or-api-gateway/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to call a command whenever there was a push on my Github repo. Since this was related to AWS tasks, I figured aws lambda is a good candidate. Here I will talk about the steps I took to enable all of this using aws lambda, python. As a side note, I will also elaborate on using API gateway to call upon the lambda itself.
In a nutshell, what I will talk about:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up custom domain with Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/setting-up-custom-domain-with-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/setting-up-custom-domain-with-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take the example of my domain itself abhipandey.com that I want to serve from abhi1010.github.io. We will need to do it in two steps:
 Setup CNAME on github  So that github knows about your domain  Setup A record on AWS Route 53  So that domain can be registered   Change CNAME If we want to tell github about the domain name, it is rather simple: create a CNAME file with the content being the name of the domain itself Do note here that the default redirect of your domain will be the value in your CNAME file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert GitHub Wiki to Static Site with themes</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/convert-github-wiki-to-static-site-with-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/convert-github-wiki-to-static-site-with-themes/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to setup a wiki so that I could convert it into a static html site with a proper themes. What could be a possible use case for such a requirement:
 Manage the documentation of a product internally through git but publish it for clients/world through static site Convert the uncolored wiki to a themed version Allow serving of the wiki through web application frameworks like Django  It may allow you to have authentication system as a first step hurdle to stop everybody from giving access   Anyways, I went about the whole process and decided to jot down everything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>