<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on Coders Digest</title>
    <link>http://abhipandey.com/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on Coders Digest</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 09:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://abhipandey.com/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crypto Volume Selector: Building a Data-Driven Tool for Cryptocurrency Trading</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2023/11/crypto-volume-selector-building-a-data-driven-tool-for-cryptocurrency-trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 09:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2023/11/crypto-volume-selector-building-a-data-driven-tool-for-cryptocurrency-trading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced world of cryptocurrency trading, making informed decisions based on market data is crucial. Today, I want to share a Python tool I&amp;rsquo;ve built that helps select cryptocurrencies based on their trading volume - a key metric that can indicate market interest and liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-trading-volume-matters&#34;&gt;Why Trading Volume Matters&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trading volume is one of the most important metrics when selecting cryptocurrencies for trading strategies. High volume typically indicates:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Better liquidity (easier to enter and exit positions)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More market interest&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Potentially lower slippage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More reliable technical indicators&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume, combined with price information, gives us the trading value - a measure of the total money flowing through a particular trading pair. This is often a more reliable indicator than just looking at price or volume in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Your Trading with TastyTrade&#39;s API</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2023/09/automating-your-trading-with-tastytrades-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2023/09/automating-your-trading-with-tastytrades-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced trading environment, automation can give you a significant edge. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a Python project that leverages the TastyTrade API to streamline various trading operations, from monitoring positions to setting automatic stop losses. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk through this integration and how it can help optimize your trading workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-integration-does&#34;&gt;What This Integration Does&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Python library acts as a wrapper around TastyTrade&amp;rsquo;s API, making it easy to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Automated Trading with Python and the Dhan API</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2023/01/mastering-automated-trading-with-python-and-the-dhan-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2023/01/mastering-automated-trading-with-python-and-the-dhan-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced financial markets, algorithmic trading has become increasingly accessible to retail investors. With the right tools and knowledge, you can automate your trading strategies and execute orders with precision. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through a comprehensive Python implementation for interacting with the Dhan trading platform&amp;rsquo;s API, which enables automated order placement, portfolio tracking, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-dhan&#34;&gt;What is Dhan?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dhan is an Indian trading platform that provides access to various financial markets through its API. This allows developers and traders to build custom trading applications, automate strategies, and manage portfolios programmatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
