<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Coders Digest</title>
    <link>http://abhipandey.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Coders Digest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abhipandey.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding launcher shortcut in Fedora</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/adding-launcher-shortcut-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/adding-launcher-shortcut-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>Many apps do not come pre-built in rpm format for Fedora so you&amp;rsquo;d have to download the tar file for it. To run the app, you would have to go to the saved folder and then either double cilck or run the command through command line. By default, that app won&amp;rsquo;t be accessible through the Super key&amp;rsquo;s universal search or as a regular application in *Show Applications.
Fortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s a way around and it is an easy one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running invoke from other folders</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/running-invoke-from-other-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:33:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/11/running-invoke-from-other-folders/</guid>
      <description>While working on big projects, sometimes, you have invoke tasks lying around in different places. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to merge them together but rather help each other out as and when needed.
One such way for this would be to search for invoke tasks from other folders and run them directly when they can be used.
I had to go for this approach for a monolithic repo where multiple projects were being built in mostly similar style with minor modifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemd tutorial</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/07/systemd-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 23:26:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/07/systemd-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Systemd usually requires two files:
 service file timer file  Service files Here you provide the details you&amp;rsquo;d use to
 Start/stop a service Define the type of service  Can be simple, forking, oneshot, dbus, notify or idle  How to kill the service Ability to restart Path for starting up Timeout for the service startup or shutdown  Service is usually made up of 3 sections:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gitlab CLI API reference</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/07/gitlab-cli-api-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 23:26:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/07/gitlab-cli-api-reference/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a short tutorial on setting up gitlab cli for yourselves. It is extremely user friendly and you can take almost any action that you need. Anything that the UI provides is also available over cli or web services - both of which have examples here.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
gitlab cli Installing the gitlab CLI # http://narkoz.github.io/gitlab/configuration gem install gitlab  Configuration export GITLAB_API_ENDPOINT=&amp;#39;http://gitlab.com/api/v3&amp;#39; export GITLAB_API_PRIVATE_TOKEN=&amp;#39;YOUR_TOKEN_&amp;#39; Available commands $ gitlab +-----------------+ | Help Topics | +-----------------+ | Branches | +-----------------+ | Commits | +-----------------+ | Groups | +-----------------+ | Issues | +-----------------+ | Labels | +-----------------+ | MergeRequests | +-----------------+ | Milestones | +-----------------+ | Namespaces | +-----------------+ | Notes | +-----------------+ | Projects | +-----------------+ | Repositories | +-----------------+ | RepositoryFiles | +-----------------+ | Snippets | +-----------------+ | SystemHooks | +-----------------+ | Users | +-----------------+ Sample CLI commands # Check the list of Projects $ gitlab projects # Based on the response, we know reconwisev2 is ID 487928 # Let&amp;#39;s find out the list of labels in it $ gitlab labels 487928 +---------------------+---------+--------------------+--------------+-------------------+---------------------------+------------+ | Gitlab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protobuf on Docker</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/protobuf-on-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 23:26:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/protobuf-on-docker/</guid>
      <description>Found it really strange that nobody had mentioned on their blog how to compile Protobuf in python with C++ implementation.
I had been having a lot of trouble with the compilation of python protobuf. After struggling with it for a few months on and off I decided to give Docker a try as I realized that my own Fedora OS may be the one having troubles. Thought of starting with Ubuntu Docker as I&amp;rsquo;ve had success with it earlier with such compilation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using TODO in Fedora</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/using-todo-in-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 21:17:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/06/using-todo-in-fedora/</guid>
      <description>I recently started using Fedora for work and had to manage a lot of tasks on various projects. The list was big enough and there&amp;rsquo;s no proper support for Evernote in linux, my trusty todo list manager or ToDo list manager by AbstractSpoon. Decided to try post-it notes but my list was changing on an ad-hoc basis. Finally came across an extension Todo.txt.
Turned out this was just what I was looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting list of Issues from JIRA under current sprint</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/05/getting-list-of-issues-from-jira-under-current-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 21:17:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/05/getting-list-of-issues-from-jira-under-current-sprint/</guid>
      <description>When you are working on Agile Boards in JIRA, you may want to retrieve all the issues related to a particular board or the sprint. Usually you&amp;rsquo;d find issues in progress under the dashboard of the sprint itself.
Python JIRA allows you only a few options:
 incompleted issues completed issues removed issues  As you will also notice from jira docs the sprints function in there only provides you sprints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getopt vs getopts</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/03/getopt-vs-getopts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 20:20:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/03/getopt-vs-getopts/</guid>
      <description>Should you use getopt or getopts in your bash scripts?
The answer can be a bit tricky but mostly straight forward.
getopt Generally, try to stay away from getopt for the following reasons:
 External utility Traditional versions can&amp;rsquo;t handle empty argument strings, or arguments with embedded whitespace For the loops to work perfectly, you must provide the values in the same sequence as the for loop itself; which is very hard to control Mostly a way to standardize the parameters  The only time I could think of using getopt is when I really want to use a long variable name and there&amp;rsquo;s just a single one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color your process listings</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/02/color-your-process-listings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/02/color-your-process-listings/</guid>
      <description>Many a times I am grepping for a process that is running on a prod server with lots of different configuration parameters. However, since there are so many of them, it is very difficult to view a particular parameter itself and find out what value was assigned to it. I wanted to make it easier on the eyes and decided to color code the parameters and separate them out from the values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a local pypi mirror</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/02/how-to-setup-a-local-pypi-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/02/how-to-setup-a-local-pypi-mirror/</guid>
      <description>It is quite easy to set up a local pypi server.
Some details can be found here. You can also use devpi if you prefer but it seems overly complicated for a job that is easily achieved by pip.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at how to use pip for local installation. Firstly, it is possible to install all requirements beforehand in a separate directory. We can use the following commands:
pip install --download DIR -r requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AngularJS 2.0 building blocks explained</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2016/01/angularjs-2.0-building-blocks-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 23:26:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2016/01/angularjs-2.0-building-blocks-explained/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s explain the eight building blocks of any Angular 2 app:
 Module Component Template Metadata Data Binding Directive Service Dependency Injection  Module  Optional feature Useful if you are using TypeScript which allows you to use interface or classes export class AppComponent is like saying that this class is going to be public Use relative file paths for importing modules  Component class is something you&amp;rsquo;d export from a module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lambda Basics with Python using Github Webhooks or API Gateway</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/11/lambda-basics-with-python-using-github-webhooks-or-api-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/11/lambda-basics-with-python-using-github-webhooks-or-api-gateway/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to call a command whenever there was a push on my Github repo. Since this was related to AWS tasks, I figured aws lambda is a good candidate. Here I will talk about the steps I took to enable all of this using aws lambda, python. As a side note, I will also elaborate on using API gateway to call upon the lambda itself.
In a nutshell, what I will talk about:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vim cannot find word list</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/vim-cannot-find-word-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 20:48:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/vim-cannot-find-word-list/</guid>
      <description>After installing spf13 vim every time I would open a file I had trouble with two things on my mac:
 File opening would halt in the middle with the following error : Cannot find word list &amp;ldquo;en.utf-8.spl&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;en.ascii.spl&amp;rdquo; Syntax highlighting also failed thereafter  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I would see:
$ vim release.sh Warning: Cannot find word list &amp;#34;en.utf-8.spl&amp;#34; or &amp;#34;en.ascii.spl&amp;#34; Press ENTER or type command to continue I googled a lot regarding this but didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up custom domain with Github Pages</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/setting-up-custom-domain-with-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/setting-up-custom-domain-with-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s take the example of my domain itself abhipandey.com that I want to serve from abhi1010.github.io. We will need to do it in two steps:
 Setup CNAME on github  So that github knows about your domain  Setup A record on AWS Route 53  So that domain can be registered   Change CNAME If we want to tell github about the domain name, it is rather simple: create a CNAME file with the content being the name of the domain itself Do note here that the default redirect of your domain will be the value in your CNAME file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forceful Docker Container cleanup on Elastic Beanstalk</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/forceful-docker-container-cleanup-on-elastic-beanstalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/10/forceful-docker-container-cleanup-on-elastic-beanstalk/</guid>
      <description>Note: If you are not sure of what you are doing here, don&amp;rsquo;t touch it. This is all sensitive stuff and a minor mistake can bring down your production.
Sometimes, because of so many deployments happening and sharing volumes between dockers instances, the space runs out on production server.
I found some ways to fix this but the most brutal way to leave the orphaned directories behind forever is to remove them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powerline for zsh</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/powerline-for-zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 08:46:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/powerline-for-zsh/</guid>
      <description>Powerline
  I was having a lot of trouble getting powerline to work on my mac machine. No matter what I tried, I was getting errors like the following:
.oh-my-zsh/themes/powerline.zsh-theme:100: character not in range Finally got it to work after multiple attempts on bash and zsh.
All I had to do was set LC_ALL to en_US.UTF-8. It would set all the locales to en_US.UTF-8 which would allow powerline fonts work properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Git Mirror With GitHub or Gitlab or Bitbucket</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/automated-git-mirror-with-github-or-gitlab-or-bitbucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 13:30:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/automated-git-mirror-with-github-or-gitlab-or-bitbucket/</guid>
      <description>Experience with Gitlab CI   Git Mirror from Gitlab to Bitbucket using Gitlab CI
  Had to move from BitBucket to Gitlab; which is really great, btw. However, there was one tiny issue here - Gitlab was not supported by Shippable. As you may know already Shippable is a hosted cloud platform that provides hosted continuous integration. We use it in our current setup to do a full testing and deployment onto AWS Elastic Beanstalk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git LOC Stats by Time Range</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/git-loc-stats-by-time-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 11:06:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/git-loc-stats-by-time-range/</guid>
      <description>Recently had an interest in seeing how many LOC were committed to the code base over a particular period of time. After some tinkering around, mainly to find out the correct format for time ranges, decided to use the following bash script for finding coding stats. Following sample is to find out lines added or removed during the year 2014.
$ git log --after=&amp;#34;2014-1-1&amp;#34; --before=&amp;#34;2014-12-31&amp;#34; --pretty=tformat: --numstat | awk &amp;#39;{ if ( $2 !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving To Hugo</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 11:14:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Create your own blog
  My blogging experience started with blogspot. It was great until I realized that I needed something that was responsive. The layout looked nice on 1024x768 but with the new generation of screens it started to look narrow. I hated the look of the website when it seemed that I was wasting a lot of white space on the web pages. I moved to wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using External Tools with Git Diff</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/using-external-tools-with-git-diff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:18:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/using-external-tools-with-git-diff/</guid>
      <description>If you want to view what has changed since one commit to another, it is quite easy to view the diff.
git diff 5fad06c..0a504fa You will get something like this:
diff --git a/modules/file_1.erb b/modules/file_1.erb index 0538da0..6621d93 100644 --- a/modules/file_1.erb +++ b/modules/file_1.erb @@ -5,8 +5,8 @@  // Algo settings &amp;#34;Carbo&amp;#34;: { - &amp;#34;active-instrument&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SGX/NK15&amp;#34;, - &amp;#34;hedge-instrument&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SGX/NK16&amp;#34;, + &amp;#34;active-instrument&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SGX/NK17&amp;#34;, + &amp;#34;hedge-instrument&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;SGX/NK18&amp;#34;,  &amp;#34;owner-app-id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;abhi1010&amp;#34;,  What if you wanted a use an external tool like meld to view the diff, in a nice beautiful side by side view?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Beanstalk Deployment Automation</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/elastic-beanstalk-deployment-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:17:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/elastic-beanstalk-deployment-automation/</guid>
      <description>We are going to talk about a setup where all you need to do it commit your code and all the rest of the steps from unit tests to deployment can be taken care of by some externally hosted cloud platform that provides continuous integration. In my case, it is going to be Shippable that I am using as a sample but you can use almost anything like TravisCI or codeship, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nginx Upload limits on Beanstalk Docker</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/nginx-upload-limits-on-beanstalk-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:14:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/nginx-upload-limits-on-beanstalk-docker/</guid>
      <description>If I am not wrong, nginx only allows you to upload up till max 2Mb of data by default. If you are doing a docker deployment on beanstalk you may to remember to change that not once but twice!
As you may know already, beanstalk creates an EC2 instance to manage the docker environment.
Since EC2 needs to manage the docker environment and serve the web interface as well, it does so by having another nginx instance to serve the nginx within docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Django Source with Docker Deployments</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/updating-django-source-with-docker-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:11:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/updating-django-source-with-docker-deployments/</guid>
      <description>While deploying docker multiple times, you may not want to copy over your Django source code every time you do a deployment.
Setting up supervisord Luckily there is an easy way to manage this. Since you are working with Django, there is a good chance that you are also managing the processes (like uwsgi) with supervisord.
Here are some of the steps that you can take with supervisord
 Set up a new process in supervisord Do not allow it to autorestart since it will be a one-shot process Call another script in any format to update the source code  As an example, I use bash to update my source code through git   Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Virtual Environments in Docker</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/multiple-virtual-environments-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 22:33:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/multiple-virtual-environments-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>It may seem like a daunting task to have multiple python projects running in their own virtual environments in docker as you want to manage the running of the tasks from a single source - let&amp;rsquo;s say supervisord. However, all that is required here is to know that python automatically picks up the location of the virtual environments if you provide full path to the virtual environment&amp;rsquo;s python.
For example, in my docker environment, I have virtual environment install at the following location:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing folders on Beanstalk Docker</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/sharing-folders-on-beanstalk-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:19:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/sharing-folders-on-beanstalk-docker/</guid>
      <description>It is very easy to setup volume sharing in docker. You ideally want the following folders to be shared when a new docker is initialized for you:
 /var/log so that you can keep track of logs nginx specific folders because you will have two instances of nginx running - one on docker and another on EC2. This allows you to share logs  Also read this post for related info  your personal workspace or anything that you&amp;rsquo;d like to share  Here&amp;rsquo;s how you&amp;rsquo;d do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert GitHub Wiki to Static Site with themes</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/convert-github-wiki-to-static-site-with-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/convert-github-wiki-to-static-site-with-themes/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to setup a wiki so that I could convert it into a static html site with a proper themes. What could be a possible use case for such a requirement:
 Manage the documentation of a product internally through git but publish it for clients/world through static site Convert the uncolored wiki to a themed version Allow serving of the wiki through web application frameworks like Django  It may allow you to have authentication system as a first step hurdle to stop everybody from giving access   Anyways, I went about the whole process and decided to jot down everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Container cleanup on Elastic Beanstalk</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/docker-container-cleanup-on-elastic-beanstalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 14:59:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/08/docker-container-cleanup-on-elastic-beanstalk/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you may notice that old containers are not cleaned up from Beanstalk environment. This may be due to your container still running as a ghost on the background. One way to find out about this is to quickly look into your /var/lib/docker/vfs/dir directory whether it has too many folders.
Next, find out what container processes you have going on. [root@ip dir]# docker ps -a
You might see something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partition Linked List around a Value X</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/partition-linked-list-around-a-value-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 15:02:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/partition-linked-list-around-a-value-x/</guid>
      <description>How do you partition a list around a value x, such that all nodes less than x come before all nodes greater than or equal to x?
Well, there are some solutions possible. The solution, I came up with, is a bit convoluted but let me tell the idea behind it. You want to track the following:
 Two pointers to remember the beginning of the lower and higher series each</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find the Kth to Last Element of a Singly Linked List</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/find-the-kth-to-last-element-of-a-singly-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2014 07:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/find-the-kth-to-last-element-of-a-singly-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to a recursive solutions but I will use a simple runner logic. Recursive solutions are usually less optimal.
Note here that, in our logic K=1 would return the last element in the linked list. Similarly, K=2 would return the second last element.
The suggested solution here is to use two pointers:
 One pointer will first travel K items into the list Once that is done, both the pointers start travelling together, one item at a time They keep travelling until the end of linked list is found In that situation, the first pointer is at the end of the list, but the second pointer would have only reached till Kth element - this is what you want  Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Duplicates from Linked List</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/removing-duplicates-from-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 16:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/removing-duplicates-from-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>Duplicates can be removed in many ways:
 Create a new Linked List containing only unique items
 Iterate through the Linked List and keep removing items that are being repeated
  The internal structure itself for the algo can either be map or set based. When using map the Node itself can be saved thereby making your life easier if you are creating a new Linked List. However sets can be very useful if we are just iterating through the Linked List and simply deleting items that are being repetetive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deleting a Node from Singly Linked List</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/deleting-a-node-from-singly-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 10:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/06/deleting-a-node-from-singly-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>Deleting a Node from Singly Linked List is rather straight forward.
 You have to know the head first of all
 Start by checking the head if that&amp;rsquo;s the one you are looking for
 Keep moving forward and checking - always check for null pointers everywhere
  Before we talk about the code, let&amp;rsquo;s see how Linked List is setup.  Now, below is the code for it&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usage of typename</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/usage-of-typename/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 14:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/usage-of-typename/</guid>
      <description>What is wrong with the following code?
 The issue is very simple but hard to notice. If you try to compile this, you will get the following errors:
main.cpp:24:5: error: need &amp;#39;typename&amp;#39; before &amp;#39;OuterStruct&amp;lt;T2&amp;gt;::InnerStruct&amp;#39; because &amp;#39;OuterStruct&amp;lt;T2&amp;gt;&amp;#39; is a dependent scope OuterStruct&amp;lt;T2&amp;gt;::InnerStruct mUsingInner; ^ main.cpp: In function &amp;#39;int main(int, char**)&amp;#39;: main.cpp:34:13: error: &amp;#39;struct InnerStruct_Wrapper&amp;lt;int&amp;gt;&amp;#39; has no member named &amp;#39;mUsingInner&amp;#39; wrapper.mUsingInner = innerStrct; The Issue
At least it straight away tells you something is wrong with InnerStruct_Wrapper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up your VIM... Your style</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/setting-up-your-vim...-your-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 15:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/setting-up-your-vim...-your-style/</guid>
      <description>Writing code using VIM can be a bit overwhelming but it helps creating a few shortcuts there to make your life easier. Here I will discuss a few.
 First of all, it is always a good idea to set up your tabs and spaces Set up shortcuts for:  Toggling of Auto-Indent while pasting source text; very useful in code (F2 in my provided script) Toggling of Auto-Scroll of Split windows (F3 in my provided script) Macro for Folding functions within the source code (@q in my provided script) Smart case search - based on whether the input is in caps or not Toggling of Mouse Usage in VIM window - to allow quick selection of text (F12 in my provided script)   Please see the provided script below to have a look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting a group of lines from a file</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/getting-a-group-of-lines-from-a-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 09:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/05/getting-a-group-of-lines-from-a-file/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this need quite a few times to pull out a section of logs that would begin with a particular line and end with another. grep is not exactly useful there because it only prints out sections based on line counters (using -A/B/C) lines based on a single search pattern.
I came up with a script that can run at almost same speeds using grep/cat/awk. awk is used to decide whether the end of the section has been reached or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>32 bit vs 64 bit</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/04/32-bit-vs-64-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/04/32-bit-vs-64-bit/</guid>
      <description>When to use 64-bit? If your application needs more than 2-4gb of data
 If your application intensively uses 64-bit arithmetic * 32-bit x86 compiled applications are restricted to x86 instruction set, even when run on on a 64-bit machine x64 supports 16 registers compared to just 8 in x86. If your code is computation intensive this may help a great deal  When to use 32-bit? After reading so many great things about 32 bit, why would anybody still want to code against 32-bit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokenize a String using C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/04/tokenize-a-string-using-c-/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/04/tokenize-a-string-using-c-/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a short snippet to split a string into multiple tokens; into a vector. As you will see that, if you run the code, boost version performs better because you can choose a number of delimiters to split your string instead of the vanilla version using the normal C++ code. Of course, you may also write your own code to do something like this but I was looking to do some short snippets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heap Sort vs Merge Sort vs Insertion Sort vs Radix Sort vs Counting Sort vs Quick Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/03/heap-sort-vs-merge-sort-vs-insertion-sort-vs-radix-sort-vs-counting-sort-vs-quick-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 05:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/03/heap-sort-vs-merge-sort-vs-insertion-sort-vs-radix-sort-vs-counting-sort-vs-quick-sort/</guid>
      <description>I had written about sorting algorithms (Tag: Sorting) with details about what to look out for along with their code snippets but I wanted a do a quick comparison of all the algos together to see how do they perform when the same set of input is provided to them. Hence I started working on a simple implementation for each one of them. I have now put together all of them in a single project on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Search in VIM</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2014/02/global-search-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2014/02/global-search-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>You must be knowing about regular VIM search
%s/SEARCH/REPLACE/CMD  However, sometimes you do not want to replace something but just see all instances of the a word or phrase. In such cases, global search is really useful when on vim. The syntax is simpler than normal search-replace:
:[range]g[lobal]/{pattern}/[cmd]  This will show all instances of the &amp;ldquo;SEARCH&amp;rdquo; term within the VIM window. There&amp;rsquo;s another version of the same command which is as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Excel in C#</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/11/reading-excel-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 23:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/11/reading-excel-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Recently had to work on an Excel and update its content when some events were triggered on a Bloomberg terminal. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any code for reading the excel file using C# so thought of putting that up.
There were a few things to learn:
 Excel support is not available by default so make sure to add Microsoft.Office.Interop.Excel as a reference
 Sometime indexing to reference the Workbooks or Worksheets may not work so try out other values</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas for Shared Memory in Linux</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/10/ideas-for-shared-memory-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 05:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/10/ideas-for-shared-memory-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing extensive research today regarding shared memory in linux before I embark on a new project in which shaving time off process communication latency is extremely important. I found some very interesting links as well. Let’s break them down:
   Topic Description Link     Theory/Explanation Some articles that explain how to get started open-std   Content in the first column Content in the second column lkd    IPC Mechanisms – some recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oracle SQL Queries</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/09/oracle-sql-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/09/oracle-sql-queries/</guid>
      <description>Recently I found myself in a situation where I had to view all the tables in the Oracle Server.
I did some digging and came up with these helpful queries.
   Query Remarks     Select * from All_Tables View all the tables in the Oracle Server   Select * from all_Views View all the views in the Oracle Server   DESC table View all the columns of a given table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVS Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/07/cvs-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 07:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/07/cvs-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on CVS for a long time now and figured out that I&amp;rsquo;d save a lot of time if I started writing alias or functions for the numerous tasks that I did on them. I will put down some of them here so you may benefit from them.
Silently update and inform about the status of the files (recursive)
cvs -q -n update  Same as earlier but will only do so for the current folder</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cursor Control in VIM Search</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/06/cursor-control-in-vim-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 07:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/06/cursor-control-in-vim-search/</guid>
      <description>Found a great way to search for keywords &amp;amp;&amp;amp; control the location of cursor in vim. It is excellent if you want to do a particular task multiple times. Usually if you search the cursor will straight away take you to the start of search. What if you want to go to the end of the word you are searching for?
/pattern/e  This takes you to the END of the keyword you are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Putty Window Title</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2013/04/change-putty-window-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 07:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2013/04/change-putty-window-title/</guid>
      <description>How to modify the Putty window title to a specific string?
By default, you&amp;rsquo;d like to have the window title to give you the full path to the folder you are working from (working directory). PROMPT_COMMANDwill help you with that.
However, if you have too many windows where you are on the same folder then it may become confusing. To set your own title you&amp;rsquo;d like to use the title() function provided here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Inheritance</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/multiple-inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/multiple-inheritance/</guid>
      <description>What is the output to the following code?
 Output
Foo FooToo Bar FootTooBar  Why?
 An instance of FooTooBar needs to be created according to main()
 To create that instance, we first need the base classes too, hence FooToo and Bar classes
 Now notice the keyword virtual everytime inheritance is defined
 This does half the magic by ensuring that the member data instances are shared with any other inclusions of that same base in further derived classes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heap Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/heap-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/heap-sort/</guid>
      <description>Heap Sort algo has the following properties:
 The top element (root) is always the next in order
 This allows you to remove one element at a time (the root) and ensure that you are pulling out items in a sorted order
 Always takes O(n*log(n)) time - worst case or best case
  Pros and cons to both   Simple implementations require additional space to hold heap of size n</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merge Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/merge-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 14:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/10/merge-sort/</guid>
      <description>Merge Sort
 Complexity is O(n log n) Needs more space to merge - proportional to the size of the array Stable Sort * Preserves the order of equal elements Merge Sort does about 39% lower comparisons, in worst case, compared to Quicksort&amp;rsquo;s average case The algo almost always behaves in the same way; taking relatively the same amount of time, whether sorted or unsorted arrays   Testing Notes  Started testing the algo with two versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/quick-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 14:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/quick-sort/</guid>
      <description>Quick Sort is an efficient divide and conquer algorithm performed in two phases - partition and sorting phase.
Here are few pointers to remember about Quick Sort:
 Partitioning places all the elements less than the pivot in the left part of the array and greater elements in the right part Pivot element stays in its place After partitioning no element moves to the other side, of the pivot * This allows you to sort the elements, to the left or right of the pivot, independent of the other side Complexity is O(n log n) Often fast for small arrays with a few distinct values, repeated many times It is a conquer-and-divide algo; with most of the work happening during partitioning phase If you had to choose the optimum pivot then it should the median of the given array Not a stable sort  Testing Notes  Currently we have only one version of the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insertion Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/insertion-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/insertion-sort/</guid>
      <description>Insertion Sort has the following properties:
 It works by moving elements one at a time Works really well for small data sets Consider going with this when the input data may already be sorted or partially sorted The may not have to move the elements around, thereby saving precious cycles Stable sort Keeps the original order of elements with equal values  Testing Notes  Had a very interesting time testing my code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radix Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/radix-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/radix-sort/</guid>
      <description>It is a non-comparative integer sorting algorithm. It sorts data by grouping keys by the individual digits which share the same significant position and value. Think Tens, Hundreds, Thousands etc. Some pointers about Radix Sort:
 Even though it is an integer sorting algorithm, it is not restricted just to integers. Integers can also represent strings of characters Two types of radix sort are:  LSD (Least Significant Digit): Short keys come before long keys MSD (Most Significant Digit) Sorting: Lexicographic Order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counting Sort</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/counting-sort/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 10:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2012/09/counting-sort/</guid>
      <description>Counting Sort is an integer sorting algorithm. It is not very famous when somebody talks about sorting algorithms but it is great when sorting integers. In fact, many a times it may even beat other Sorting Algorithms. The highlight of Counting Sort is that it creates a bucket array (to keep track of frequency of numbers) whose size is the maximum element in the provided array.
We are looking to compare most of the sorting algorithms to find out which one performs better under different circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio 2008 crashes while adding items</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/05/visual-studio-2008-crashes-while-adding-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/05/visual-studio-2008-crashes-while-adding-items/</guid>
      <description>Had this problem cropping up since months where I was trying to add items to Visual Studio 2008 Toolbox and it kept crashing.
Finally got a work around, you should start it in safe mode. Here&amp;rsquo;s the procedure:
devenv /safemode  Then use Choose Items on toolbox and run through each of the tabs. Once you accept any exceptions raised on loading controls, you can then open Visual Studio normally and add items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Analytics &amp; SWFAddress</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/04/google-analytics-swfaddress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 05:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/04/google-analytics-swfaddress/</guid>
      <description>Recently found a bug slash issue with Google Analytics new javscript software (post-urchin v5). I had written the internal documentation for the company standards and somehow when those standards were put into practice, SWFAddress feature of flash stopped working the moment google analytics feature was enabled. Worst of all, the web pages failed to load! To cap it off, the website was working perfectly fine on Firefox 2, 3 and IE 7!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Trust on Mapped Drive</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/full-trust-on-mapped-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/full-trust-on-mapped-drive/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, when opening a web project from another mapped drive (not your own computer&amp;rsquo;s hard disk) Visual Studio may complain something like this:
The project location is not trusted. Running the application may result in security exceptions when it attempts to perform actions which require full trust.  The problem here is that .Net does not want to fully adhere to all security policies as your hard disk to this mapped drive as well as it does not know what kind of data it might have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tag your namespaces</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/tag-your-namespaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 08:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/tag-your-namespaces/</guid>
      <description>Recently discovered a nifty little feature on .Net and though of sharing it.
You can tag an assembly by giving it a name and then use this name throughout your class to access the classes inside this namespace.
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#0000ff;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;using&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; asp=CompanyName.Data;  Now all the classes inside CompanyName.Data namespace can be accessed using the name asp (as if it was an instance of the namespace).
One thing to note, however, is that the classes inside this namespace cannot be accessed directly and the word &amp;ldquo;asp&amp;rdquo; has to be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to protect from SQL Injections in ASP.NET</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/how-to-protect-from-sql-injections-in-asp.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2008 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/how-to-protect-from-sql-injections-in-asp.net/</guid>
      <description>Some good links to figure out how to save your code&amp;rsquo;s ass from being thrashed by SQL Injections
http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms998271.aspx#paght000002_step2
http://msdn2.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb355989.aspx#paght000003_step4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Custom Web Controls</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/creating-custom-web-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/creating-custom-web-controls/</guid>
      <description>How do you extend a control? Let&amp;rsquo;s figure it out.
Why would you want to extend existing controls?
Because some functionality may not exist exactly as you may need it. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s take up ImageButton control example. It is a great control but it falls short when it comes to real world scenario. Mostly websites do a hover image clickable button where the text or background color of the button changes once you hover your mouse over it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StringBuilder vs String joins</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/stringbuilder-vs-string-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 13:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/stringbuilder-vs-string-joins/</guid>
      <description>For those who do not want to waste their time, here&amp;rsquo;s the gist for this whole article: StringBuilder performs better but you should try to use it when there&amp;rsquo;s lot of concatenation involved (normally more than 7 joins - start thinking about StringBuilder.
Let&amp;rsquo;s move on for the lesser mortals. There has been a lot of debate about using StringBuilder instead of adding string like
&amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#606060;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; 1:&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; strVariable += &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;color:#006080;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot; Add this string to my variable string&amp;quot;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;;  What&amp;rsquo;s the darn difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs I like</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/blogs-i-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2008 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/blogs-i-like/</guid>
      <description>Two blogs i really like and follow many a times are:
SqlAuthority.com - Excellent blog for Sql Server 2005. The guy has a very in-depth knowledge of Sql Server and I appreciate the way
Scott&amp;rsquo;s Blog - Another great blog where Scott Guthrie talks quite a bit about ASP.NET and tells the latest details coming in from Microsoft.
Just today I found another interesting blog. This guy talks about the interesting aspects in programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursively read directories and list all files under it</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/recursively-read-directories-and-list-all-files-under-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 07:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/recursively-read-directories-and-list-all-files-under-it/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk to my... Flash?</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/talk-to-my...-flash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 04:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/03/talk-to-my...-flash/</guid>
      <description>According to normal acceptable behaviour it is not possible to let flash talk to the computer, be it on desktop or web browser.
There are always ways around a problem and there&amp;rsquo;s one in this case as well.
Windows Forms
If you wanted to access .net functions on windows form then probably a good way to do that would be through ShockWaveFlashObjects library. It wraps all the functions that are available in ShockWave Objects and makes them available to you in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Membership and Profiler in ASP.NET</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2008/02/membership-and-profiler-in-asp.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 19:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2008/02/membership-and-profiler-in-asp.net/</guid>
      <description>Whenever you are using Sql Membership and Profiler classes - Trying to generate reports make sure your query&amp;rsquo;s WHERE clause is using &amp;ldquo;indexed&amp;rdquo; column names at least.
Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the more used tables. The index of some of the tables is given below:
Table: aspnet_membership
 Clustered Index = ApplicationID, LoweredEmail
 NonClustered = UserID
  Table: aspnet_users
 Clustered Index = ApplicationID, LoweredUserName
 NonClustered Index = ApplicationID, LastActivityDate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Head First Design Patterns</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2007/12/book-review-head-first-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2007 02:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2007/12/book-review-head-first-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>What an amazing book this is! It is a must read for any developer who wants to develop long term codes/projects.
The book looks at mostly the more important design patterns. The distinctive feature that stands out in this book is how it manages to make each pattern stand out against each other. It gives comparison between similar-looking patterns where necessary. It make the patterns &amp;ldquo;debate&amp;rdquo; against each other, get the birds-eye-view from &amp;ldquo;patterns guru and grasshopper discussion&amp;rdquo;, UML like &amp;ldquo;class diagrams with notes&amp;rdquo; to show how everything is gelling together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically increase Label size [AutoSize]</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2007/11/dynamically-increase-label-size-autosize/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 07:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2007/11/dynamically-increase-label-size-autosize/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had to work on a windows form where the Labels are added dynamically onto the form. Some of you may think that setting AutoSize to true would fix the problem but it works only when you already have added that Label control onto the form, not when you are adding it dynamically.
Despair not, there&amp;rsquo;s still a solution. Just create a label and set it&amp;rsquo;s text first then call this function:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use of yield statement</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2007/10/use-of-yield-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2007 16:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2007/10/use-of-yield-statement/</guid>
      <description>It might be a little late for this to appear but I have no qualms in accepting that I have finally embraced yield statement and see it as an excellent way of writing codes.
I have had my fair share of writing small code fragments to read/process/write files and more often than that it is excel files. So I thought, there has to be an easier way than just creating common functions for Connections and processing functions - at that time yield statement came to the rescue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>