<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supervisord on Coders Digest</title>
    <link>http://abhipandey.com/tags/supervisord/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supervisord on Coders Digest</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:17:10 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://abhipandey.com/tags/supervisord/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic Beanstalk Deployment Automation</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/elastic-beanstalk-deployment-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:17:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/elastic-beanstalk-deployment-automation/</guid>
      <description>We are going to talk about a setup where all you need to do it commit your code and all the rest of the steps from unit tests to deployment can be taken care of by some externally hosted cloud platform that provides continuous integration. In my case, it is going to be Shippable that I am using as a sample but you can use almost anything like TravisCI or codeship, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Django Source with Docker Deployments</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/updating-django-source-with-docker-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:11:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/updating-django-source-with-docker-deployments/</guid>
      <description>While deploying docker multiple times, you may not want to copy over your Django source code every time you do a deployment.
Setting up supervisord Luckily there is an easy way to manage this. Since you are working with Django, there is a good chance that you are also managing the processes (like uwsgi) with supervisord.
Here are some of the steps that you can take with supervisord
 Set up a new process in supervisord Do not allow it to autorestart since it will be a one-shot process Call another script in any format to update the source code  As an example, I use bash to update my source code through git   Here&amp;rsquo;s a sample code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Virtual Environments in Docker</title>
      <link>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/multiple-virtual-environments-in-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 22:33:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://abhipandey.com/2015/09/multiple-virtual-environments-in-docker/</guid>
      <description>It may seem like a daunting task to have multiple python projects running in their own virtual environments in docker as you want to manage the running of the tasks from a single source - let&amp;rsquo;s say supervisord. However, all that is required here is to know that python automatically picks up the location of the virtual environments if you provide full path to the virtual environment&amp;rsquo;s python.
For example, in my docker environment, I have virtual environment install at the following location:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>